A big part of my motivation for making
this course came from a tweet, a post on
X that the incredible Andre Karpathy
made a few months ago. And I put the
tweet up here. Andre Capathy, of course,
he's one of the founding members of
OpenAI. He's been uh you know across
across his work at at Tesla and OpenAI
and at Stanford. He is just such a
luminary in the industry. And uh he's
also the person that coined the term
vibe coding, as we'll find out later.
And this was a tweet that he came up
with uh late last year. And I'm going to
do the slightly unusual thing of reading
this tweet to you, but adding some
expression to it cuz I think it's it's
so incredible. Andre says, "I've never
felt this much behind as a programmer.
The profession is being dramatically
refactored as the bits contributed by
the programmer are increasingly sparse
and between. I have the sense that we
could be 10x more powerful if I could
just properly string together what's
become available over about the last
year. And a failure to claim that boost
feels like a skill issue. There's this
new layer of abstraction to in addition
to to the usual layers that involves
agents, sub aents, their prompts,
context, memory, modes, permissions,
tools, plugins, skills, hooks, MCP, LSP,
slash commands, workflows, ID
integrations, and the need to build an
all-encompassing mental model for
strengths and pitfalls of fundamentally
stochastic, fallible, unintelligible,
and changing entities suddenly
intermingled with what used to be good
old-fashioned engineering.
Wow, what a tweet. And then Andre ends
the tweet with, "Clearly some powerful
alien tool was handed around, except it
comes with no manual, and everyone has
to figure out how to hold it and operate
it while the resulting magnitude 9
earthquake is rocking the profession.
Roll up your sleeves to not fall
behind." And in a nutshell, that that
tweet is what this course is all about.
This course, as I said at the beginning,
it is the missing manual. The idea is
that at the end of this course, you'll
be able to bring back up this tweet and
read that through and you'll be able to
say, "Yes, yes, yes. I know what all
these things mean. I know how they fit
together. I know where they work well,
where they don't work. I can separate
the the the hype from the facts. and I
know how to navigate this crazy new
world of agentic AI coding. That is what
I have in store for you over 3 weeks.
So, who exactly is this intended for? Is
it meant for people who are junior or
for people who are senior coders, never
coded before, you're an expert? Well,
here's the answer. It's for two
different types of people. First of all,
aspiring engineers. People who maybe are
junior or not technical at all today.
Maybe this is one of your first times
ever writing code or maybe you've
written a bit but but you consider
yourself not yet an expert. You will be
able to build complete products
largecale products with confidence with
the assistance of AI agents. And the
other archetype, the other person that
I'm that I'm targeting this course for
is actually people who are senior staff
engineers, people who are experienced
coders. either relatively new to the
agentic AI coding or you you feel a bit
like Andre's tweet. You feel like like
like there's just too much going on. How
do you navigate all these different
things? How do you work them together to
to accelerate the most? And that's what
this is about. I I'm going to allow you
to accelerate what you can do to
maximize the potential and importantly
to keep enjoying what you do because a
lot of what drives the passion for being
an engineer for for me and for you is
about solving problems and building
great stuff and there's this sense out
there that some of these AI tools are
taking away the enjoyment and I don't
think that needs to be the case. I think
it changes the picture. It means some
things that I used to enjoy I don't do
anymore, but there are new things that I
enjoy that I can now do. And so it's a
it's a change in the equation. It's a
change in what we can do. And there's
stuff to enjoy out of that as well. And
I I know you know I'm going to say this,
but of course I'm going to say that it's
not actually for those two archetypes of
person. Uh you you have to be either an
aspiring engineer or a senior staff
engineer. Of course, the idea is that
there will be something in this for
everyone. I'm going to talk to people
that are relatively new to coding or
completely new and to the experts too.
This is something that connects the
dots. And as a result, there'll be some
things that might be too advanced for
you and that's okay. Just get a gist of
it and keep moving. And for the experts,
there's going to be some stuff like how
to set up cursor, what's what's a
project directory. There's going to be
super obvious to you. And don't worry,
just put me on 2x. Zoom through that.
There's going to be tons of juicy stuff
here. There's going to be something for
everyone across the spectrum of your
technical experience. And so what will I
leave you with at the end of our three
weeks together? You will be able to
build and debug and troubleshoot and
enhance existing software products at
any scale. Whether it's a small whether
it's a first person shooter game or
whether it's a large team collaboration
with with a massive repo or multiple
repos. Whatever scale, whatever kind of
problem you're working on, you will be
able to do it assisted by AI agents. You
will be able to take the greatest
advantage of the current landscape. In
other words, you'll be able to to tweet
back at Karpathy at Andre and say, "I
get all this. I know how to navigate it.
I have the missing manual." And thirdly,
and importantly, of course,
increasingly, if you look at job
descriptions, people expect that that
you have these kinds of skill sets. So
you're able to use Agentic AI to help
you write code more efficiently and
you'll be able to apply to those jobs
and show that you have the full skill
set. You know about MCP and skills and
hooks and so on and and even Ralph Loops
and how to bring it all together to
deliver highquality software fast. And
by the way, I just want to clarify
something that that you'll hear me say a
lot, which is that whilst I am an upbeat
type. I'm generally an enthusiast, I I'm
not caught up in the Agentic AI hype,
the the tools that we're going to be
using in the next few few weeks are
incredibly powerful and allow us to do
amazing things, but they are not without
their downsides. There are significant
benefits and there are also drawbacks.
And I'm going to make you very aware of
those drawbacks. And being successful
using Agentic AI to write software is
about knowing about both the strengths
and the weaknesses and being able to
maximize the strengths and being able to
manage the weaknesses and that is what
we will be